now that we have seen pshare and gshare
let's do a quiz about them let's say
that we have this fragment of C code
where I goes from 1,000 down to zero and
for odd numbered eyes we are going to
add the I to n otherwise we just don't
do it this code might translate into
assembler program like this this Branch
here is the test for exiting this Loop
when R1 is zero this is testing the
least significant bit of R1
and if that bit is zero that means we
have an even number so we jump to the
even label if the number is odd then we
add it to R3 which in this case is
representing n either way we decrement
the R1 this is the IUS minus and we
unconditionally Branch back to the loop
and the exit label for exiting the loop
is here if we want to get good accuracy
on all of the branches in this code then
the history should be how much for
pshare right the number here and for
gshare write the number here so we're
just talking about how many bits of
History we need to get good prediction
accuracy for all of these branches